Okay so we've taken our lump of clay.
We centered it.
We've opened it and we've raised the walls.
So essentially we have a finished form of a mug on our hands here.
But we want to make another one that's exactly the same.
So what we're going to do is we're going to take these two tools here and we're going to start by measuring the height of the mug like this.
And as you can see we can measure it quite accurately.
And we can say that is the exact height of this mug.
Like that.
Okay?
And that is now our measurement.
Tighten up the end so it doesn't move.
Over here, the little wing nut.
Okay so now we have measured the height of our mug.
And we're going to now measure the top lip.
Use this tool.
Very similar tool.
It's just a little smaller.
We're going to measure it and there you can see we have it measured.
This will give us an accurate measurement of the top lip of the mug so that we can make our second mug.
And we will get to that after we do the finishing part on this mug.
We have one more step to do with this.
And then we will move on.